RYAN C ANDERSON - WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Ryan C. Anderson is a web developer passionate about problem solving and writing elegant and efficient code. While he presently mostly writes in Ruby and Javascript, he has interest and past experience in a wide variety of frameworks and languages. In addition, he has a love and talent for learning new technologies and working in a team.

PROJECTS

Aggredile – Personal Project – <u>www.aggredile.com</u> - (2014 – Present)

- Minimalistic Feedly clone, written using Rails and Backbone.js.
- News aggregator, allowing users to subscribe to and follow RSS feeds.
- Designed and implemented database to hold user authentication and feed information.
- Designed and implemented RESTful api to control interaction between client and host.

Asteroids and Lasers - Personal Project - www.rycander.com/asteroids - (2014 - Present)

- · Game written in Javascript, inspired by Asteroids.
- Wrote game from the ground up using Javascript and html5 canvas.

Sonar – University of California – <u>www.sonar-game.com</u> - (2011 - 2012)

- Survival/stealth game with a blind protagonist, written in C# using XNA.
- · Created level loading system, and collision handling/detecting system.
- Designed and implemented data mining system exporting game info to xml.
- Designed and implemented a heat map program using data from xml.

WORK EXPERIENCE

RETAXY – Lead Software Engineer (2015 - 2016)

- · Designed customer facing web page in React.
- Hosted Rails back end on Heroku, with asset storage on Amazon.
- Worked within tight time constraints as only member of the engineering team.

KATO – Software Engineer (2014 - 2015)

- Worked to help clean up new user experience for chat web client.
- Worked to help transition client from being written in Javascript and Knockout.js to being written in Typescript and React.

INTEL – Junior Engineer (2013 - 2014)

- Worked as part of a scrum team meant to maintain a Ruby test suite that generated assembly to be run on prototype graphics hardware.
- · Was responsible for identifying and repairing tests that were failing due to errors in test logic.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science – University of California Santa Cruz (2008 – 2012)

SKILLS

Agile Scrum, Backbone.js, Bootstrap, C, C++, C#, CSS, Eclipse, Git, Heroku, HTML, Jasmine, Java, Javascript, JSON, jQuery, Linux, Mac OS, OpenGL, PERL, PostreSQL, Python, Rails, React, Rspec, Ruby, SQLite, SVN, TDD, UML Design, Unity 3D, Visual Studio, Windows, XML, XNA

CONTACT

Phone: (510) 325-5311
Email: ryan@rycander.com
Portfolio: rycander.com
GitHub: github.com/rycander

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/pub/ryan-anderson/37/36a/61a</u> Location: 1963 Clemens Rd, Oakland, CA 9460